# **Emil Reji**

■ emil315.reji@gmail.com • Greater NYC Area, USA ★ https://emilreji.github.io/

#### **Profile**

I'm a full stack Software Engineer based in the Greater New York City Area. I am a co-creator of Stagehand Framework, a drop-in service for automatically deploying and managing review apps for front end applications. I have experience in a variety of technologies including, but not limited to the Ruby and JavaScript Ecosystems. I also have extensive experience working with cloud environments such as AWS, Docker, Github Actions, etc.

# **Professional Experience**

### Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand-Framework

08/2020 - present

https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑

- Co-Created Stagehand, an open-source drop-in solution that automates review apps for frontend applications
- Designed and implemented the AWS infrastructure using a Cloudfront CDN, IAM Permissions, Cloudformation Automation, Lambda@Edge Functions, S3 Buckets, and EC2 Instances
- Used Github Actions to automate review app creation and tear down in response to Github events
- Used service workers and other client side code to implement a dashboard for the review app users while simultaneously solving our complex routing issues
- Created an npm package to provide a simple CLI that pulls together Stagehand's architecture
- Co-authored documentation for the npm package
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑
- Collaborated daily with the rest of Stagehand's remote team

#### **Software Engineer, Senior Associate, Infosys**

09/2018 - 08/2020

- Worked as a tester and a developer using Java, Spring, Oracle, SQL, Python, Angular, Jenkins, Agile, etc.
- Was selected as part of Infosys's #FlyingHigh Associate Success Stories
- Worked remotely across multiple time zones world wide

#### **Skills**

# Back EndFront EndCloudTooling/OtherNode.js, Express, Ruby,<br/>Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, SQL,<br/>MongoDB, REST API's,<br/>GraphQL, Webhooks, JavaJavaScript (ES6), React,<br/>Redux, HTML/CSS, Gatsby,<br/>Next.js, jQueryAWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku,<br/>VercelGit/Github, Docker, Jenkins,<br/>Agile Development

#### **Education**

#### Bachelors of Science in IT, Minor in Computer Science,

2014 - 2018

Montclair State University

• GPA of 3.725 on a 4.0 scale

## **Information Security Certificate,**

2016 - 2017

County College of Morris